Sheets are where we can build visualizations.
الأوراق هي المكان الذي يمكننا من خلاله إنشاء مؤثرات عرض.
Let's go over some of the various areas on the screen.
فلنبدأ باستكشاف بعض المناطق الأخرى على الشاشة.
At the top, we have the menus.
في الجزء العلوي، لدينا القوائم.
Menus contain a lot of powerful options and I
تحتوي القوائم على الكثير من الخيارات القوية
recommend clicking through to see which options they have.
وأوصي بالاطلاع على الخيارات المتاحة.
The logo button here brings us back to the start experience,
إن زر الشعار هنا يعيدنا إلى تجربة البداية،
where we can access saved data sources,
حيث يمكننا الوصول إلى مصادر البيانات المحفوظة،
recently opened or pinned workbooks.
أو المصنفات التي تم فتحها أو تثبيتها مؤخرًا.
To the left of the screen is the data pane.
يوجد على يسار الشاشة جزء البيانات.
If we're on the Data tab,
إذا كنا في علامة تبويب البيانات،
the topless all open data sources and depending on which one is selected,
سنجد جميع مصادر البيانات المفتوحة وهذا يتوقف على العناصر المحددة منها،
the fields from that data source are listed below,
ويتم سرد الحقول من مصدر البيانات أدناه،
broken out into dimensions and measures.
مقسمة إلى أبعاد ومقاييس.
The data pane will also show any sets or parameters we have.
سيعرض جزء البيانات أيضًا أي مجموعات أو معلمات لدينا.
If we open the maps layer or the format pane,
إذا فتحنا طبقة الخرائط أو جزء التنسيق،
these temporarily cover the data pane.
فإنها تغطي مؤقتًا جزء البيانات.
If we click on the analytics tab,
إذا نقرنا فوق علامة تبويب التحليلات،
we can bring out pieces of our analysis directly as drag and drop elements.
يمكننا تقديم أجزاء من تحليلنا مباشرةً كعناصر سحب وإفلات.
If they're not relevant to the type of view,
إذا لم تكن ذات صلة بنوع العرض،
certain elements will be grid out,
فسيتم فصل عناصر معينة،
such as totals on a timeline.
مثل الإجماليات على مخطط زمني.
If we select something like a trend line,
إذا اخترنا شيئًا مثل خط الاتجاه،
we can bring it out to any of these drop down areas to control aspects of its properties,
فإنه يمكننا إخراجه إلى أي من هذه المناطق المنسدلة للتحكم في جوانب خصائصه،
like model type or which measure it should be applied to.
مثل نوع الطراز أو القياس الذي يجب تطبيقه عليه.
New sheets are found down here at the bottom.
تم العثور على أوراق جديدة هنا في الأسفل.
We can create sheets,
يمكننا إنشاء أوراق
dashboards or stories with these tabs.
أو لوحات معلومات أو قصص مع علامات التبويب هذه.
We can do things like, rename sheets,
يمكننا القيام بأشياء مثل، إعادة تسمية الأوراق،
duplicate sheets, copy formatting, many other things.
وتكرار الأوراق، ونسخ التنسيق، والعديد من الأشياء الأخرى.
Finally and perhaps more importantly, we have the shelves.
وأخيرًا، وربما الأهم من ذلك، لدينا الرفوف.
These can be built by dragging and dropping fields from
يمكن بناؤها عن طريق سحب الحقول وإفلاتها
the data pane into the canvas directly or onto shelves.
من جزء البيانات إلى اللوحة مباشرة أو على الأرفف.
Shelves are sometimes referred to as cards.
يشار إلى الأرفف في بعض الأحيان على أنها بطاقات.
There's the column shelf and the row shelf up here,
يوجد رف الأعمدة ورف الصفوف هنا،
the pages and filter shelves and the marks cards.
والصفحات وأرفف الترشيح وبطاقات العلامات.
The marks card is made up of several other shelves,
تتكون بطاقة العلامات من عدة رفوف أخرى،
each of which can have fields placed on
يمكن أن يحتوي كل منها على حقول موضوعة
them and can be clicked on to edit the characteristics.
عليها ويمكن النقر فوقها لتحرير الخصائص.
Changing the marks type can change the shelves on the marks cards such as,
يمكن أن يؤدي تغيير نوع العلامات إلى تغيير الرفوف الموجودة على بطاقات العلامات،
selecting shape brings up the shape shelf.
مثل اختيار الشكل الذي يؤدي إلى جلب رف الشكل.
Depending on the composition of the view,
اعتمادًا على تركيبة العرض،
there can be multiple marks cards, one for each measure.
يمكن أن تكون هناك بطاقات علامات متعددة، واحدة لكل قياس.
Legends such as color, size and shape,
سيتم إنشاء وسائل إيضاح مثل اللون والحجم والشكل
will automatically be created when a field is placed on the color,
تلقائيًا عندما يتم وضع حقل على لون رف
size or shape shelf.
أو حجمه أو شكله.
However, legends can be removed by clicking on the menu and selecting hide card.
ومع ذلك، يمكن إزالة وسائل الإيضاح من خلال النقر فوق القائمة وتحديد إخفاء البطاقة.
To bring the legend back,
لإرجاع وسيلة الإيضاح،
right click anywhere off the canvas itself,
انقر بزر الماوس الأيمن فوق أي مكان خارج اللوحة نفسها،
select legend and choose the one you want.
وحدد وسيلة الإيضاح واختر ما تريد.